ILGWU Publication "Gerechtigkeit" (Justice) Digital Files from Microfilm 5780/185 mf(d)
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Publication "Gerechtigkeit" (Justice) Digital Files from Microfilm
1919-1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/185 mf(d)
1.22 cubic feet
11 microfilm reels
DVDs, electronic reproductions.
This collection contains issues of Gerchtigheit, the Yiddish-language edition of the ILGWU's official organ Justice.
8433722
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 27, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Justice was the official organ of the ILGWU from 1919 to 1995. Editions of Justice were published in English, Italian, Spanish, and Yiddish. When compared side by side, the content of some of these different editions of Justice shows significant differences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/070: ILGWU Publication "The Ladies' Garment Worker" 5780/070 mf: ILGWU Publication "The Ladies' Garment Worker" on Microfilm 5780/125: ILGWU Newspapers 5780/185 mf: ILGWU Publication "Gerechtigkeit" (Justice) on Microfilm
8433722
- Jan.17, 1919-Apr 30, 1920 - vol. 1-2; reel 01, 1919-1920; 1 (Reel 1)
- May 7, 1920-Dec 30, 1921, vol. 2-3; reel 02, 1920-1921; 1 (Reel 2)
- Jan 6, 1922-Aug 31, 1923, vol 4-5; reel 03, 1922-1923; 1 (Reel 3)
- Sept 7, 1923-May 15, 1925, vol 5-7; reel 04, 1923-1925; 1 (Reel 4)
- May 22 1925-May 27, 1927, vol 7-9; reel 05, 1925-1927; 1 (Reel 5)
- Jun 3, 1927-Jul 25, 1930, vol 9-12; reel 06, 1927-1930; 1 (Reel 6)
- Aug 8, 1930-Dec 1937, vol 12-19; reel 07, 1930-1937; 1 (Reel 7)
- Jan 1938-Apr 1942, vol 20-24; reel 08, 1938-1942; 1 (Reel 8)
- May 1942-Jul 1946, vol 24-28; reel 09, 1942-1946; 1 (Reel 9)
- Aug 1946-Dec 1951, vol 28-33; reel 10, 1946-1951; 1 (Reel 10)
- Jan 1952-Jan 1958, vol 34-40; reel 11, 1952-1958; 1 (Reel 11)